<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name></name>
        <update version="1.0.0">
            <file name="wizard-dimensionalism.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Zenoverlordian/Aurora-Builder-Yorviings-Arcane-Grimoire/main/wizard-dimensionalism.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="School of Dimensionalism" type="Archetype" source="Yorviing's Arcane Grimoire" id="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_WIZARD_DIMENSIONALISM">
        <supports>Arcane Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Wizards who follow the tradition of dimensionalism focus on portals, rifts, and teleportation, favoring spells that increase their mobility and teleporting prowess. Known as ‘portaliers’ or ‘rift mages’, these wizards learn spells of teleportation and can eventually trap others within portals that seemingly never end. Many followers of dimensionalism are avid travelers to other planes, and are often nomadic.</p>
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DIMENSIONALISM_PORTAL_SAVANT" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DIMENSIONALISM_SPELL_RIFTS" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DIMENSIONALISM_QUICK_STEP" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DIMENSIONALISM_EXPERT_TELEPORTER" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DIMENSIONALISM_DIMENSION_TRAP" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DIMENSIONALISM_PORTAL_SAVANT" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DIMENSIONALISM_SPELL_RIFTS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DIMENSIONALISM_QUICK_STEP" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DIMENSIONALISM_EXPERT_TELEPORTER" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DIMENSIONALISM_DIMENSION_TRAP" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Portal Savant" type="Archetype Feature" source="Yorviing's Arcane Grimoire" id="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DIMENSIONALISM_PORTAL_SAVANT">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 2nd level, you have acquired considerable knowledge regarding portals, planes, and teleportation. The gold and time you must spend to copy a spell that allows you to teleport yourself or others into your spellbook is halved.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, whenever you make an Intelligence (Arcana) check when interacting with portals and teleportation, your Proficiency bonus is doubled if it applies to the check.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>The gold and time you must spend to copy a spell that allows you to teleport yourself or others into your spellbook is halved. Additionally, whenever you make an Intelligence (Arcana) check when interacting with portals and teleportation, your Proficiency bonus is doubled if it applies to the check.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Spell Rifts" type="Archetype Feature" source="Yorviing's Arcane Grimoire" id="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DIMENSIONALISM_SPELL_RIFTS">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 2nd level, you have learned how to open up rifts in space through which you can cast your spells. Whenever you cast a wizard spell of 1st level or higher with a duration of Instantaneous, as part of the casting of this spell, you can choose to open up a rift or portal in a 5 foot unoccupied space that you can see within 60 feet of you. You rift or portal can deliver the spell as if it had cast the spell.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you use this feature, you can't cast spells other than cantrips until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you cast a wizard spell of 1st level or higher with a duration of Instantaneous, as part of the casting of this spell, you can choose to open up a rift or portal in a 5 foot unoccupied space that you can see within 60 feet of you. You rift or portal can deliver the spell as if it had cast the spell. When you use this feature, you can't cast spells other than cantrips until the end of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Quick Step" type="Archetype Feature" source="Yorviing's Arcane Grimoire" id="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DIMENSIONALISM_QUICK_STEP">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level, you know how to move you or your allies in the blink of an eye when in danger. When either you or an ally that you can see within 30 feet of you take damage, you can use your reaction to cause either yourself or your ally to teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature on a creature, you can't use it again until your finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description action="Reaction" usage="1/Short Rest">When either you or an ally that you can see within 30 feet of you take damage, you can use your reaction to cause either yourself or your ally to teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Expert Teleporter" type="Archetype Feature" source="Yorviing's Arcane Grimoire" id="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DIMENSIONALISM_EXPERT_TELEPORTER">
        <description>
            <p>By 10th level, you have become adept at teleporting far distances. As an action, you and a number of willing creatures of your choice that you can see within 60 feet of you teleport up to 1 mile to a spot you can see. If there isn’t an open space for all the targets to occupy at the arrival point, this ability fails and is wasted.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you have used this feature, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description usage="1/Long Rest" action="Action">As an action, you and a number of willing creatures of your choice that you can see within 60 feet of you teleport up to 1 mile to a spot you can see. If there isn’t an open space for all the targets to occupy at the arrival point, this ability fails and is wasted.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Dimension Trap" type="Archetype Feature" source="Yorviing's Arcane Grimoire" id="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DIMENSIONALISM_DIMENSION_TRAP">
        <description>
            <p>By 14th level, you know how to trap your enemy within a series of rifts and portals. As an action, choose a creature that you can see. That creature must make a Wisdom saving throw or be pulled into a portal that transports the target into another plane. The creature disappears and hurtles through another plane.</p>
            <p class="indent">At the beginning of your next turn, the target returns to an unoccupied space of your choice within 60 feet of you and immediately must make another Wisdom saving throw or be pulled back into another portal. This effect continues for 1 minute or until the target succeeds on a saving throw against this ability.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you have successfully used this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description action="Action" usage="1/Long Rest">As an action, choose a creature that you can see. That creature must make a Wisdom saving throw or be pulled into a portal that transports the target into another plane. The creature disappears and hurtles through another plane.
            At the beginning of your next turn, the target returns to an unoccupied space of your choice within 60 feet of you and immediately must make another Wisdom saving throw or be pulled back into another portal. This effect continues for 1 minute or until the target succeeds on a saving throw against this ability.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
</elements>