<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    
    <element name="Doomsayer" type="Archetype" source="Yorviing's Arcane Grimoire" id="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_WIZARD_DOOMSAYER">
        <supports>Arcane Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The incredibly rare tradition known as Doomsaying involves the art of seeing into the future to witness the ending of one’s self, others, or a kingdom itself. Wizards who follow this tradition are known as doomsayers, and are those who dared to expose themselves to the dreaded knowledge of divining the future to wield the magic of final moments. Some wizards who practice this tradition witness the end and see it as a way of knowing how much time is left to make a difference in the world, while others see it as a true source of power as they know how and when their enemies will crumble into dust.</p>
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_ENDINGS_AFTERMATH" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_FINALITYS_MOMENTS" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_MORTALITYS_FEAR" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_DESTRUCTIONS_WRATH" />
            <div element="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_DOOMS_PERSISTENCE" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description>The incredibly rare tradition known as Doomsaying involves the art of seeing into the future to witness the ending of one’s self, others, or a kingdom itself.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_ENDINGS_AFTERMATH" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_FINALITYS_MOMENTS" level="2" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_MORTALITYS_FEAR" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_DESTRUCTIONS_WRATH" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_DOOMS_PERSISTENCE" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Ending's Aftermath" type="Archetype Feature" source="Yorviing's Arcane Grimoire" id="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_ENDINGS_AFTERMATH">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning when you select this tradition at 2nd level, you have peered into the future and have seen your doom, and have learned how to stop it. When you or an ally within 30 feet of you is reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you can use your reaction to make either yourself or your ally drop to 1 hit point instead.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can't use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description usage="1/Long Rest" action="Reaction">When you or an ally within 30 feet of you is reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you can use your reaction to make either yourself or your ally drop to 1 hit point instead.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Finality's Moments" type="Archetype Feature" source="Yorviing's Arcane Grimoire" id="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_FINALITYS_MOMENTS">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 2nd level, you have learned how to harness the power released from a creature’s final moments. Once per turn when you kill one or more creatures with a spell of 1st level or higher, you can deal necrotic damage equal to half your wizard level to each creature within 5 feet of a creature who was killed.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Once per turn when you kill one or more creatures with a spell of 1st level or higher, you can deal {{level:wizard:half}} necrotic damage to each creature within 5 feet of a creature who was killed.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Mortality's Fear" type="Archetype Feature" source="Yorviing's Arcane Grimoire" id="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_MORTALITYS_FEAR">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level, you can call upon the fearful presence of doom to your enemies. Once per turn, whenever a creature fails a saving throw against a spell that you cast of 1st level or higher, that creature becomes frightened of you for 1 minute. The frightened target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once the effect ends, or if the creature succeeds on its initial saving throw against this effect, you can't use this feature on that creature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Once per turn, whenever a creature fails a saving throw against a spell that you cast of 1st level or higher, that creature becomes frightened of you for 1 minute. The frightened target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. Once the effect ends, or if the creature succeeds on its initial saving throw against this effect, you can't use this feature on that creature again until you finish a long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Destruction's Wrath" type="Archetype Feature" source="Yorviing's Arcane Grimoire" id="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_DESTRUCTIONS_WRATH">
        <description>
            <p>At 10th level, you have learned how to bring forth the destructive power of your spells. Your spell attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19-20.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your spell attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19-20.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Doom's Persistence" type="Archetype Feature" source="Yorviing's Arcane Grimoire" id="ID_YORVIING_YAG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DOOMSAYER_DOOMS_PERSISTENCE">
        <description>
            <p>By 14th level, the dread of doom will come, even if you are not there to see it. When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, any active spell that you had cast before you were reduced to 0 hit points that has a duration longer than Instantaneous continues as if you are still concentrating on the spell.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, any active spell that you had cast before you were reduced to 0 hit points that has a duration longer than Instantaneous continues as if you are still concentrating on the spell.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
</elements>